Ahmed M. Ibrahim El-bastawisi

Software Engineer · Mansoura, Egypt

<u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>GitHub</u>

+20 1013162775 · ahmedbastawisi@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology sector. Skilled full stack .NET developer. Strong engineering professional with a bachelor's degree focused on Computer Science from Computer Engineering and Systems, Mansoura University.

Technical Skills

C#, ASP.NET Core MVC, Entity Framework Core, SQL, SignalR, Webrtc, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Angular

Achievements

- **Graduation Project:** Autonomous Car System, navigate complex environments switching between different behaviors (go to goal, avoid obstacles, follow wall)
- Responsibilities: Design and test different algorithms using Matlab based Simulator (Sim.Lam)
- Graduation Project Grade: Distinction
- Udacity Advanced Web Development Nanodegree (October, 2020)

Experience

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE Co. W.L.L

Software Engineer Jan 2019 – May 2023 Cairo, Egypt

Work with Web development team to create enterprise resource planning (ERP) SaaS Application.

- Design a web-based project management software
- Improving system quality by identifying issues and common patterns
- Track issues and fix bugs
- Deploying product updates

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE Co. W.L.L

Junior Software Engineer Jan 2018 – Jan 2019 Cairo, Egypt

Work with Web development team to create enterprise resource planning (ERP) SaaS Application.

- Assist the development team with all aspects of software design and coding
- Learn the codebase and attend design meetings
- Track issues and fix bugs

Education

Computer Engineering and Systems, Mansoura University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering, 2012-2017

Cumulative Grade: 72.15 % (good)

Personal Skills

- Hard-working, Minute to Detail
- High-level of maturity and sense of responsibility
- Sound time management skills
- Ability to work in a team driven environment

Languages

- Arabic (Native proficiency)
- English (Professional working proficiency)

Personal Information

Birth Date: August 1, 1994Marital Status: Single

• Military Status: Exempted